（二十年前）
I still don't know why I'm here。Couldn't you just make them say yes？
我还是不明白要我来干吗？ 你就不能直接让他们答应？
Yes，I could，but it's not my way.
当然能，但那不是我的作风
And I would expect you，of all people，would understand my feelings on misuse of power.
而且我希望你，跟其他所有人 能理解我对滥用超能力的立场
Ah，power corrupts and all that。Yes，I know，Charles.
不要用超能力干坏事 我都知道了，查尔斯
- When are you going to stop lecturing me？- When you start listening.
- 你啥时能别总教育我了？ - 你也得听啊
You're here because I need you.
让你来是因为我需要你
We don't have to meet every one of them in person？
我们不用每一个都亲自拜访吧？
No。This one's special.
不用，但这个很特别
What a beautiful campus。John，don't you think？
校园环境真好啊 约翰，你说呢？
Yeah，the brochure is great.
嗯，介绍很不错
But what about Jean？What about her illness？
但琴怎么办？ 她的病怎么办？
- lllness？- John.
- 病？ - 约翰
You think your daughter is sick，Mr。Grey？
你认为你女儿有病，葛雷先生？
Perhaps it would be best if we were to speak to her。Alone.
最好能让我们单独跟她谈谈
Of course.
当然
Jean，can you come down，dear？
琴，下楼来好吗？
We'll leave you，then.
那你们谈吧
It's very rude to read my thoughts，or Mr。Lensherr's，without our permission.
擅自监听我们的思想是很不礼貌的
Did you think you were the only one of your kind，young lady？
你以为就你会特异功能吗，小姐？
We're mutants，Jean。We're like you.
我们是变种人，琴 我们跟你一样
Really？I doubt that.
真的？我不太想信
Oh，Charles.
哦，查尔斯
I like this one.
我喜欢她
You have more power than you can imagine，Jean.
你的超能力远强于此，琴
The question is，will you control that power？
问题是，你能控制它
Or let it control you？
还是被它控制？
（十年前）
Warren？Son，is everything all right？
沃伦，儿子，你没事吧？
- What's going on？- Nothing。I'll be right out.
- 怎么了？ - 没什么，我马上出来
Come on。You've been in there for over an hour.
快点，你都进去快一个小时了
Open the door。Warren.
开门，沃伦
One second！
等一下！
Open this door.
开门
Warren.
沃伦
Let me in there right now。Open the door.
立刻让我进去，开门
Oh，God.
天啊
- Not you。- Dad，I'm sorry.
- 你不该 - 爸爸，对不起
《X战警3：背水一战》
（不远的未来）
The whole world's going to hell and you're just going to sit there？Let's go.
人间都快成地狱了，你们还干坐着？ 我们走
Bobby！
鲍比！
Thanks，Kitty.
谢了，基蒂
- We're getting killed out here。- Yeah，I know。They're not ready，Storm.
- 我们死定了 - 对，我知道，他们没准备好呢，暴风女
- Logan。- Oh，don't get your panties in a bunch.
- 洛根 - 哦，别大惊小怪的
That was my last cigar.
那是我最后一根雪茄
Logan.
洛根
- It's getting closer。- Come on。Let's keep moving.
- 越来越近了 - 快点，快闪吧
Hey，Tin Man。Come here.
嘿，铁樵夫，过来
- How's your throwing arm？- Logan，we work as a team.
- 胳膊没生锈吧？ - 洛根，我们该并肩作战
Yeah。Good luck with that。Throw me。Now.
是啊，祝君好运了，扔我上去，快
Dammit，Logan，don't do this.
该死，洛根，别这样
Class dismissed.
下课
Hey，Colossus。Nice throw.
嗨，巨匠，扔得好
Simulation complete.
仿真结束
- What was that？- Danger room session.
- 那算什么？ - 危情演习
- You know what I mean。- Lighten up.
- 你明白我指什么 - 别当回事
You can't change the rules。I'm trying to teach 'em something.
你不能坏了规矩 我正试图教他们些东西
- I taught 'em something。- It was a defensive exercise.
- 我已经教了 - 那该是防御练习
Yeah，best defense is a good offence。Or is it the other way round？
对，进攻就是最好的防守
- This isn't a game，Logan。- Well，you sure fooled me.
- 这不是游戏，洛根 - 那你还真骗到我了
Hey，I'm just a sub。You got a problem，talk to Scott.
嘿，我就是个代课的 你有意见，找斯科特说去
- Scott！- Jean.
- 斯科特！ - 琴
Scott。Scott.
斯科特 斯科特
Scott.
斯科特
- Are you OK？- I'm fine.
- 你没事吧？ - 我很好
You seem like you're avoiding me。Something's wrong.
你像是总在躲着我 有啥不对劲的？
I can't touch my boyfriend without killing him。Other than that I'm wonderful.
除了一碰我男朋友他就会挂掉 我几近完美
Hey。I don't think that's fair。Have I ever put any pressure on you？
嘿，这不公平 我给过你压力吗？
You're a guy，Bobby。Your mind's only on one thing.
你是男的，鲍比 你脑子里只有一根筋
- They were looking for you。You didn't show。- What do you care？
- 他们正找你呢，你没去上课 - 你瞎操什么心？
- For starters，I had to cover your ass。- I didn't ask you to.
- 首先，我得替你收拾残局 - 我可没求你
No，you didn't。The professor did.
你是没有，但教授有
- I was just passing through。- So pass through，Logan.
- 我只是路过 - 那就赶紧过，洛根
Hey，look.
嘿，你看
- I know how you feel。When Jean died… - Don't.
- 我理解你的感受，琴死的时候… - 别说了
Maybe it's time for us to move on.
是时候该重新振作了
Not everybody heals as fast as you，Logan.
没人像你一样好得那么快，洛根
（变种人事务部）
（《科学美国人》 变种人探秘）
- Mr。Secretary。- Yes.
- 部长先生 - 什么事？
- The meeting's begun，sir。- Thank you.
- 会议开始了，先生 - 谢谢你
Mr。President.
总统先生
Have a seat，Hank.
坐吧，汉克
Homeland Security was tracking Magneto.
国土安全部正在追踪万磁王
We got hits in Lisbon，Geneva，Montreal.
我们追查到里斯本，日内瓦，蒙特利尔
NAVSAT lost him crossing the border，but we did get a consolation prize.
卫星在他过境的时候跟丢了 但我们有个安慰奖
We picked her up breaking into the FDA.
我们在她闯入FDA时逮到的 （FDA：美国食品及药物管理局）
You know who she's been imitating？Secretary Trask here.
你猜她当时变成谁了？ 就是崔萨克部长本人
Yes，sir。She can do that.
的确，她能做到
- Not any more，she can't。We got her。- You think your prisons can hold her？
- 以后就不行了，我们抓到她了 - 你认为你的监狱能关住她？
We have some new prisons。We'll keep them mobile。Be a step ahead.
我们有新型监狱 这次要先发制人
Where is Magneto？
万磁王在哪儿？
Raven？
瑞文
- Raven，I asked you a question。- I don't answer to my slave name.
- 瑞文，我在问你话 - 我不叫这种奴隶名字
Raven Darkholme。That's your real name，isn't it？
瑞文·达克霍姆 那是你的真名，不对吗？
Or has he convinced you you don't have a family any more？
看来他让你相信你没有家人了？
My family tried to kill me，you pathetic meat sack.
我的家人想杀了我 你个可怜的大草包
OK，then。Mystique，where is he？
好吧，魔形女，他在哪儿？
In here with us.
就在这里
I don't want to play games with you。I want answers.
我不想跟你在这玩游戏 我要答案
You don't want to play games with me？
你不想跟我玩游戏？
You are going to stop this。Tell me，where is Magneto？
别变了 告诉我万磁王在哪儿？
You wanna know where he is？
你想知道他在哪儿？
Homo sapien.
智人（人类的学名）
You know，her capture will only provoke Magneto，
抓到她只会激怒万磁王
but having her does give us some diplomatic leverage.
但她的确是个重要筹码
On principle，I can't negotiate with these people.
按理说，我不跟这些人谈条件
- I thought that's why you appointed me，sir。- Yes，it is.
- 我还以为您为此才委任我 - 是，没错
- But that's not why you called me here。- No。This is.
- 但这不是你叫我来的原因 - 不，这才是
It's what she stole from the FDA.
这是她从FDA偷的东西
Dear Lord.
老天
- Is it viable？- We believe it is.
- 这能行吗？ - 我们相信能
You realize the impact this'll have on the mutant community？
您知道这会在变种人中造成多大的反响？
Yes。I do。That's precisely why we need some of your diplomacy now.
知道，所以我才找你
When an individual acquires great power，
当一个个体获得了超能力
the use or misuse of that power is everything.
能否正确使用它才是关键
Will it be for the greater good or will it be used for personal or for destructive ends？
是学雷锋还是谋私利 抑或是搞破坏？
Now，this is a question we must all ask ourselves.
这些我们都该扪心自问
Why？Because we are mutants.
为什么？因为我们是变种人
For psychics，this presents a particular problem.
心理学上，这是一个微妙的问题
When is it acceptable to use our power and when do we cross that invisible line
何时可以使用超能力 而何时我们又会失控
that turns us into tyrants over our fellow man？
成为凌驾于同伴之上的暴君？
But Einstein said that ethics are an exclusive human concern
但爱因斯坦说，伦理观念
without any superhuman authority behind it.
是不牵扯超能力的人文关怀
Einstein wasn't a mutant so far as we know.
起码现在据我们所知 爱因斯坦不是变种人
This case study was sent to me by a colleague，Dr。Moira McTaggert。Jones.
这个案例分析是默瑞亚·迈克泰格寄来的 琼斯
The man you see here was born with no higher-level brain functions.
你们见到的这个人， 天生没有高级脑功能
His organs and nervous system work，but he has no consciousness to speak of.
他的各器官跟神经系统正常 但他没有说话的意识
What if we were to transfer the consciousness of one person，
我们能不能把别人的意识
say a father of four with terminal cancer，
比如一个癌症末期，有四个孩子的父亲
into the body of this man？
移植到这个人身上？
How are we to decide what falls within the range of ethical behavior and what…
如何界定这种行为 是否符合伦理道德，而什么…
Professor？
教授？
We'll continue this tomorrow。Class dismissed.
我们明天再继续 下课
The forecast was for sunny skies.
天气预报说今天艳阳高照
I'm sorry.
对不起
I don't have to be psychic to see that something's bothering you.
不用透视你的思想， 我就能看出来你的烦恼
I don't understand。Magneto's a fugitive，
我不明白，万磁王是个逃犯
we've a mutant in the cabinet，a president who understands us，why hide？
我们在内阁里有个变种人 总统也理解我们，干嘛要躲？
We're not hiding。But we still have enemies。I must protect my students。You know that.
我们不是躲，但敌人还是存在 我必须保护我的学生，你知道
Yes，but we can't be students forever.
对，但我们不能做一辈子学生
Storm，I haven't thought of you as my student for years.
暴风女，我早就不把你当学生看了
In fact，I thought that perhaps you might take my place some day.
实际上，我打算以后让你来 接替我的位子
- But Scott's… - Scott's a changed man.
- 但斯科特的… - 斯科特变了
He took Jean's death so hard.
他把琴的死看得太重
Yes，things are better out there，
对，现在外面形势好些了
but you，of all people，know how fast the weather can change.
但你，你们所有人， 知道这世事有多无常
There's something you're not telling us.
有事你没告诉我们
Hank？
汉克？
Ororo。Charles.
奥拉若，查尔斯
I love what you've done with your hair.
我喜欢你的新发型
You too。Thank you for seeing me on such short notice.
你的也不错 谢谢你这么快就来见我
Henry，you are always welcome here。You're a part of this place.
亨利，这里永远欢迎你 你是这里的一分子
- I have news。- Is it Eric？
- 我有个消息 - 是埃里克？
No。Though we have been making some progress on that front.
不，但那方面也有些进展
- Mystique was recently apprehended。- Who's the fur ball？
- 魔形女最近被捕了 - 这毛球是谁？
Hank McCoy。Secretary of Mutant Affairs.
汉克·麦考伊，变种人事务部部长
Right，right。The secretary。Nice suit.
对，对，部长大人，西装不错
- Henry，this is Logan。He's… - Wolverine.
- 亨利，这是洛根，他是… - 金刚狼
- I hear you're quite an animal。- Look who's talking.
- 听说你绝对是个禽兽 - 彼此彼此
Magneto's gonna come get Mystique.
万磁王会营救魔形女
Magneto's not the problem。At least not our most pressing one.
万磁王不是问题 至少不是最棘手的
A major pharmaceutical company has developed a mutant antibody.
有家医药公司研发出了一种 变种人抗体
A way to suppress the mutant X gene.
可以抑制住变种Ｘ基因
- Suppress？- Permanently.
- 抑制？ - 永久的
They're calling it a cure.
他们叫它解药
That's ridiculous。You can't cure being a mutant.
真荒唐 做变种人是无药可解的
- Scientifically speaking… - When did we become a disease？
- 从科学上讲… - 我们什么时候成疾病了？
Storm.
暴风女
They're announcing it now.
他们正在开发布会
These so-called mutants are people just like us.
这些所谓的变种人 与你我毫无二致
Their affliction is nothing more than a disease，
他们的痛楚有如疾病一样
a corruption of healthy cellular activity.
不过是细胞恶化造成的
But I stand here today to tell you that there's hope.
但今日我站在这里是想告诉你们 还有希望
This site，once the world's most famous prison，
这里，曾是世界闻名的监狱
will now be the source of freedom for all mutants who choose it.
如今将它成为一个自由之源， 帮助那些想恢复正常的变种人
Ladies and gentlemen…
女士们，先生们…
I proudly present the answer to mutation.
我在此自豪的向大家介绍 治愈变种的方法
Finally，we have a cure.
终于，我们有解药了
Who would want this cure？I mean，what kind of coward would take it just to fit in？
谁会想要这解药？ 哪个胆小鬼会为了融入社会用这玩意？
Is it cowardice to save oneself from persecution？
从迫害中解救自己也叫胆小？
Not all of us can fit in so easily.
不是所有人都能轻松融入的
- You don't shed on the furniture。- The government probably cooked this up.
- 你是站着说话不腰疼 - 这也许只是政府编出来的
- The government had nothing to do with it。- I've heard that before.
- 这一切与政府无关 - 这话我以前听过
My boy，I have been fighting for mutant rights since before you had claws.
小子，你还没爪子的时候 我就开始捍卫变种人权了
- Did he just call me boy？- Is it true？They can cure us？
- 他刚管我叫小子？ - 是真的吗？他们能治好我们？
Yes，Rogue。It appears to be true.
对，小淘气，看来是真的
No。Professor.
不，教授
They can't cure us.
他们不能治愈我们
You wanna know why？Because there's nothing to cure。Nothing's wrong with you.
想知道为什么？因为没什么 好治愈的，你根本就没毛病
Or any of us，for that matter.
我们都没有毛病
How should we，as mutants，respond？Here's what I think.
作为变种人，我们该如何回应？ 我是这么想的
This is about getting organized。Bringing our complaints to the right people.
我们该团结起来 将诉求告知当权者
We need to put together a committee and talk to the government.
我们该成立一个委员会 与政府谈判
They don't understand。They don't know what it means to be a mutant.
他们不明白，他们不知道 作为变种人的意义
We need to show them，educate them，let them know that we're here to stay.
我们要展现给他们，教育他们 让他们知道，我们想保持现状
People，you must listen。They won't take us seriously…
诸位，你们必须听着 他们不会重视我们…
- They wanna exterminate us。- This cure is voluntary.
- 他们要灭绝我们 - 接受治疗是自愿的
Nobody is talking about extermination.
没人说过什么灭绝
No one ever talks about it.
根本没人会去说
They just do it.
他们直接就做了
And you'll go on with your lives ignoring the signs all around you.
你们就这样继续苟且偷生
And then one day，when the air is still and the night has fallen，they come for you.
迟早有一天，当夜幕降临 他们会来找你
Then you realize，while you're talking about organizing and committees，
到时候你才会意识到 当你还在谈论组织委员会时
the extermination has already begun.
灭绝行动早已展开了
Make no mistake，my brothers。They will draw first blood.
别犯错误，兄弟们 他们会先挑起事端
They will force their cure upon us.
他们会强迫我们接受治疗
The only question is，will you join my brotherhood and fight？
唯一的问题是 你愿意加入我的兄弟会并肩战斗？
Or wait for the inevitable genocide？
还是等待必将来临的大灭绝？
Who will you stand with？The humans？
你要拥护谁？人类？
Or us？
还是我们？
You talk pretty tough for a guy in a cape.
穿得这么严实，话倒是很露骨啊
Back off.
退后
If you're so proud of being a mutant，where's your mark？
既然你如此为变种人骄傲 那你的标记呢？
I have been marked once，my dear。Let me assure you.
我被标记过一次，亲爱的 我保证
No needle shall ever touch my skin again.
绝不允许别人再这么干了
You know who you're talking to？
你知道在跟谁说话吗？
Do you？
你知道吗？
And what can you do？
你有什么能耐？
So you have talents？
这就是你的天赋？
That and more。I know you control metal.
不止这个，我知道你能控制金属
And I know there's 87 mutants in here，none above a class three.
我还知道这里有87个变种人， 都达不到三级
Other than you two.
除了你们俩之外
You can sense other mutants and their powers？
你能感知其他变种人跟他们的能力？
Could you locate one for me？
能帮我去找个人吗？
Let me out of here。I demand that you release me.
让我出去 我命令你放了我
Do you know who I am？I'm the president of the United States.
知道我是谁？ 我是美国总统
Oh，Mr。President.
哦，总统大人
Shut up.
闭嘴
Why are you doing this to me？Let me down。I'll be a good girl。Please let me go.
你为什么这样对我？放我下来 我会做个乖孩子，放了我吧
Please.
求你了
Keep it up。I'll spray you in the face，bitch.
再废话，我就往你脸上喷这个 小贱货
When I get out of here，I'm going to kill you myself.
等我出去了 一定亲手杀了你
Yeah，right.
好啊
Secretary McCoy，welcome to Worthington Labs.
迈考伊部长 欢迎来沃星顿实验室
Thank you，Dr。Rao。Not an easy place to get to.
谢谢，娆博士 来这可不容易啊
It's the safest location we could find。That's why we keep the source of the cure here.
这是能找的最安全的地方 所以把解药的药方存在这
He is a mutant。You understand our concern.
他是个变种人，你明白我们的顾虑
- We are in compliance with your policy。- How long will you keep the boy here？
- 我们一直遵照您的政策 - 你要把那孩子关多久？
Until we can fully map his DNA。We can replicate it，but we can't generate it.
直到我们绘制出他全部的DNA 我们只能复制，但不能制造
And his power？What is its range？
那他的能力，属于哪一级？
You'll see.
你会看到的
Jimmy.
吉米
There's someone I would like you to meet.
我介绍你认识个人
Hello there，son.
你好啊，孩子
- Hi。- My name is Hank McCoy.
- 嗨 - 我叫汉克·麦考伊
I'm sorry.
对不起
It's OK.
没关系
You have an amazing gift。Thank you，Jimmy.
你有个很神奇的才能，谢谢，吉米
Extraordinary，isn't he？
天赋异禀，是不是？
Yes，he is.
的确
Scott.
斯科特
- Can you hear me？I'm still here。Scott。- Stop.
- 能听见我吗？我一直在这，斯科特 - 住嘴
- I'm here。Scott。Scott。- Stop it.
- 我在这，斯科特，斯科特 - 别说了
- Scott。Scott。- Stop it.
- 斯科特，斯科特 - 别说了
I need you，Scott。Scott。Scott.
我需要你，斯科特，斯科特，斯科特
Stop！
住嘴
Jean？
琴？
Scott.
斯科特
How？
怎么会？
I don't know.
我不知道
I wanna see your eyes.
我想看看你的眼睛
- Take these off。- No.
- 摘掉它 - 不
No.
不
Trust me。I can control it now.
相信我，我能控制它
Open them。You can't hurt me.
睁开，你不会伤到我
- What happened？- No clue.
- 怎么了？ - 不清楚
- Professor，are you OK？- Get to Alkali Lake.
- 教授，你还好吗？ - 快去奥克莱湖
- You don't want to be here。- Do you？
- 你不想来 - 你想？
I can't see a damn thing.
我啥都看不见
I can take care of that.
我来解决这雾
What the…
这他妈…
Logan！
洛根
She's alive.
她没死
Jean.
琴
The sheer mass of water that collapsed on top of Jean should have obliterated her.
速降的水流本应另她 粉身碎骨
The only explanation of Jean's survival
琴之所以能存活下来
is that her powers wrapped her in a cocoon of telekinetic energy.
只可能是她的能量为她 做了一个像茧子般的异能保护层
Is she gonna be OK？
她会没事吗？
Jean Grey is the only class five mutant I've ever encountered，her potential limitless.
琴·葛雷是我遇到的唯一一个 五级变种人，她的能量是无限的
Her mutation is seated in the unconscious part of her mind and therein lay the danger.
她的突变存在于潜意识中 而且埋下了危险隐患
When she was a girl，I created a series of psychic barriers
当她还是孩子时， 我制造了一系列精神屏障
to isolate her powers from her conscious mind.
来把她的力量与意识隔绝开
- Jean developed a dual personality。- What？
- 所以琴发展成了双重人格 - 什么？
The conscious Jean，whose powers were always in her control，and the dormant side.
清醒的琴，力量总由她所支配 而那个处于休眠状态的
A personality that，in our sessions，came to call itself the Phoenix.
人格，我们称之为凤凰
A purely instinctual creature，all desire and joy and rage.
纯粹的人类本性，充满欲望、享乐和愤怒
- She knew all this？- It's unclear how much she knew.
- 她知道这些？ - 不清楚她知道多少
Far more critical is whether the woman in front of us is the Jean Grey we know，
关键是面前这个是 我们所熟知的琴·葛雷
or the Phoenix furiously struggling to be free.
还是强烈渴望自由的凤凰
- She looks peaceful to me。- I'm keeping her that way.
- 我看她挺安详的 - 是我让她这样的
I'm trying to restore the psychic blocks and cage the beast again.
我正试图重建精神屏障 将兽性困于其中
What have you done to her？
你对她作了什么？
- You have to understand… - You're talking about a person's mind.
- 你应该理解… - 你是在说一个人的头脑
- She has to be controlled。- Controlled？
- 她需要被控制住 - 控制住？
Sometimes，when you cage the beast，the beast gets angry.
有时候，物极必反
You have no idea。You have no idea of what she is capable.
你无法想象 你无法想像她能做什么
No，Professor。I had no idea what you were capable of.
不，教授 我无法想象你能做什么
I had a terrible choice to make。I chose the lesser of two evils.
我必须作个可怕的选择 我从两个恶魔中选择了危害最小的
It sounds to me like Jean had no choice at all.
在我看来是琴别无选择
I don't have to explain myself，least of all to you.
我不需要为自己辩解 你自己来分辨吧
History will be made here today。For the first time，
今天是历史性的一刻 首次
the so-called mutant cure will be available to the public.
所谓的变种人解药 将公之于众
Reaction has run the gamut with mutants on both sides of the line.
变种人两派声势都很强烈
Some are desperate for this cure while others are offended by the very idea of it.
有人求药若渴， 而其他人则对此气愤异常
Will Secretary McCoy be a problem？
迈考伊部长那边会有麻烦吗？
Hard to say。His political views seem somewhat at odds with his personal issues.
很难说，他的政见与他本人一样怪异
Excuse me，sir。Your son's arrived.
打扰一下，先生，您儿子到了
Good。Bring him in.
好，带他进来
Are you sure you want to start with him？
你真想从他开始？
I think it's important。Yes.
我觉得这很重要，是的
- Hello，Warren。- How are you，son？
- 你好，沃伦 - 怎么样，儿子
- Did you sleep well？- Yeah.
- 睡得好吗？ - 还行
You know，I'm proud of you for doing this.
我很骄傲你能参加
Everything's gonna be fine。I promise.
一切都会好的，我保证
You ready？
准备好了？
The transformation can be a little jarring.
转变过程可能会有些不适
- Dad，can we talk about this for a second？- We've talked about it，son.
- 爸，我们能再谈谈吗？ - 我们已经谈过了，儿子
It'll all be over soon.
很快就会过去
- Everything's going to be fine。- Wait。I can't do this.
- 一切都会好的 - 等等，我不能这么做
Warren，calm down.
沃伦，别激动
- I can't do this。- Yes，you can.
- 我不能这么做 - 你能
- I can't do this。- Just relax，son。Take it easy。Calm down.
- 我不能这么做 - 放松点，孩子，别紧张，冷静
- I promise you it will be fine。Warren，relax。- Dad.
- 我保证会没事的，沃伦，放松 - 爸爸
Warren，it's a better life.
沃伦，那将是更好的生活
- It's what we all want。- No.
- 那是我们所期望的 - 不是
It's what you want.
那是你所期望的
Warren，no！
沃伦，别！
Told you so.
我说啥来着
About time.
挺准时啊
I've been busy。Did you find what you were looking for？
一直很忙， 找到你要找的东西了吗？
The source of the cure is a mutant。A child at Worthington Labs.
解药的配方是一个变种人 一个沃星顿实验室里的小孩
Without him，they have nothing.
没了他，他们一无是处
Read off the guest list.
读读乘客名单
「Cell 41205。James Madrox.」
41205单元，詹姆斯·迈罗克斯
This one robbed seven banks.
这家伙打劫了七家银行
- At the same time。- I could use a man of your talents.
- 同时同刻 - 我能用到你的天赋
- I'm in。- Welcome to the Brotherhood.
- 算我一个 - 欢迎加入兄弟会
- Careful with this one。- 「Cain Marko。Solitary confinement.」
- 小心这家伙 - “科因·马可，单独隔离”
Check this out。「Prisoner must be confined at all times.」
听听这个：“囚犯必须永久隔离”
「lf he builds any momentum，no object can stop him.」
“一旦发力，将所向匹敌”
How fascinating.
太刺激了
- What do they call you？- Juggernaut.
- 他们叫你什么？ - 神像
- I can't imagine why。- Are you going to let me out？I need a pee.
- 我想不出原因 - 你能让我出去吗？我要尿尿
- Nice helmet。- Keeps my face pretty.
- 头盔不错 - 我戴着很帅吧
I think he'll make a fine addition to our army.
我想他会令我军实力大增
No！
不
You saved me.
你救了我
Eric.
埃里克
I'm sorry，my dear.
对不起，亲爱的
You're not one of us any more.
你不再是我们的一员了
Such a shame。She was so beautiful.
真是丢人，她原来多美啊
Think resigning will make a difference？That's no way to influence policy.
你辞职就能管用吗？ 这是动摇不了政策的
Policy is being made without me，Mr。President.
我没参与制定政策，总统先生
The decision to turn the cure into a weapon was made without me.
将解药制成武器没经我同意
What happened on that convoy was inexcusable。But your actions…
押运车队的事的确不能原谅 但您的行动…
That was an isolated incident。You have to understand those mutants were a real threat.
那是一次孤立事件 你该清楚那些变种人相当危险
Have you even begun to think what a slippery slope you're on？
你就一点没想过你这是铤而走险？
I have.
我想过
And I worry about how democracy survives when one man can move cities with his mind.
我还担心当超能力泛滥时 还有民主可谈吗？
As do l.
我也担心
You and I know that it's only going to get worse.
你我都知道它只会变得更糟
All the more reason why I need to be where I belong.
显然我该回到属于我的地方去了
Jean.
琴
- Hi，Logan。- Welcome back.
- 嗨，洛根 - 欢迎回来
Back where we first met。Only I was in your place and you were in mine.
回到我们初次见面的地方 你中有我 我中有你
Are you OK？
你还好吧？
Yeah.
好
More than OK.
很好
Logan，you're making me blush.
洛根，你让我难为情
- You're reading my thoughts？- I don't have to.
- 你在透视我的思想 - 我不需要
It's OK.
没关系
- Wait。- No.
- 等等 - 不
Jean.
琴
- This isn't you。- Yes，it is me.
- 这不是你 - 是，是我
No。Maybe you ought to take it easy.
不，你该冷静一下
The professor said you might be different.
教授说你可能会不同
He would know，wouldn't he？
他会知道，是不是？
What？You think he's not in your head too？
什么？你不觉得他在监视你？
Look at you，Logan。He's tamed you.
看看你自己，洛根，他驯服了你
Where's Scott？
斯科特在哪儿？
Jean？
琴？
- Where am l？- You're in the mansion.
- 我在哪儿？ - 你在学校
You need to tell me what happened to Scott.
你得告诉我斯科特怎么了
Jean，tell me what happened to him.
琴，告诉我他怎么了
Oh，God.
老天
Look at me.
看着我
Stay with me。Talk to me.
保持清醒，跟我说话
- Look at me。Look at me。- No.
- 看着我，看着我 - 不
Focus。Focus，Jean.
集中精力，集中精力，琴
Kill me.
杀了我
- What？- Kill me before I kill someone else.
- 什么？ - 在我杀别人前先杀了我
- Don't say that。- Please.
- 别那样说 - 求你了
- Stop it。- Kill me.
- 别说了 - 杀了我
Stop it。Look at me。Look at me。Jean.
别说了，看着我，看着我，琴
It'll be all right。We can help you.
没事的，我们能帮你
Hey。The professor can help。He can fix it.
嘿，教授能帮你，他能治好你
I don't want to fix it.
我不想治
Voluntary？They put the cure in a gun.
自愿？他们把解药装在抢里？
I told you they would draw first blood.
我就说他们会先挑起事端
- So what do we do？- What do we do？
- 那我们怎么办？ - 我们怎么办？
We use this weapon as a lightning rod to bring countless more to our cause.
我们以此为借口， 血债血偿，加倍奉还
Come。We have an army to build.
来吧，我们要建立一支军队
I picked something up.
我发现个东西
An electromagnetic force。It's massive.
一个电磁能场，很殷实
It's a mutant.
是个变种人
Class five。More powerful than anything I've ever felt.
五级 比我之前感觉到的都强大
More powerful than you.
比你都强大
Where is she？
她在哪儿？
Logan.
洛根
- Jean。Jean。- What happened？
- 琴，琴 - 发生什么了？
What have you done？
你干什么了？
- I think she killed Scott。- What？
- 我认为他杀了斯科特 - 什么？
- That's not possible。- I warned you.
- 那不可能 - 我警告过你
She's left the mansion，but she's trying to block my thoughts。She's so strong.
她离开了学校，但她试图 屏蔽我的意念，她很强大
It may be too late.
也许太迟了
- Wait for me here。- What？
- 在这等我 - 什么？
I need to see Jean alone.
我要单独去见琴
You were right，Charles.
你是对的，查尔斯
- This one is special。- What the hell are you doing here？
- 这一个很特别 - 你他妈在这干吗？
Same as the professor。Visiting an old friend.
跟教授一样，拜访老友
- I don't want trouble here。- Nor do l.
- 我不想在这生事 - 我也不想
So，shall we go inside？
那么，我们进去吧？
I came to bring Jean home。Don't interfere.
我是来带琴回家，别妨碍我
- Just like old times，eh？- She needs help。Jean is not well.
- 就像上次，嗯？ - 她需要帮助，她情况不好
Funny，you sound just like her parents.
有趣，你的口气就像她父母
Nobody gets inside.
别让任何人进来
- I knew you'd come。- Of course。I've come to bring you home.
- 我知道你会来 - 当然，我来带你回家
- I have no home。- Yes，you do。You have a home and a family.
- 我没有家 - 你当然有，你有家跟家人
You know he thinks your power is too great for you to control.
他觉得你的能力对你来说太强了
I don't believe your mind games are going to work any more，Charles.
你的意念游戏不管用了，查尔斯
- So you want to control me？- He does.
- 那你想控制我？ - 他是想
No。I want to help you.
不，我想帮你
Help me？What's wrong with me？
帮我？我有问题吗？
- Absolutely nothing。- Eric，stop.
- 绝对没有 - 埃里克，闭嘴
No，Charles，not this time。You've always held her back.
不，查尔斯，这次不行 你总是拖她后腿
For your own good，Jean.
为你自己好，琴
Stay out of my head.
别进到我意识里来
- I'm going in。- The professor said he'd handle this.
- 我要进去 - 教授说他能应付
Look at me，Jean。I can help you。Look at me.
看着我，琴，我能帮你，看着我
Get out of my head.
从我意识里出去
- Perhaps you should listen to her，Charles。- Trust me。You're a danger to everyone.
- 你也许该听她的，查尔斯 - 你一定要相信我，你对所有人都很危险
- But I can help you。- I think you want to give her the cure.
- 但我能帮你 - 我猜你是想给她解药
Look at Scott。You killed the man you loved because you couldn't control your power.
看看斯科特，你杀了你所爱的人 因为你没能控制你的能量
No！Stop it！
不！别说了！
That's it.
进去吧
Jean，let me in.
琴，让我进去
No，Jean.
不，琴
Jean！
琴！
Don't let it control you.
别让它控制你
Charles.
查尔斯
My dear。Come with me.
亲爱的，跟我走
No.
不
God！
天啊
We live in an age of darkness.
我们生活在黑暗的时代
A world full of fear，hate and intolerance.
恐慌遍布四野，仇恨与偏见
But in every age，there are those who fight against it.
但每个时代， 都会有人挺身反抗
Charles Xavier was born to a world divided.
查尔斯·泽维尔生于一个破裂的世界
A world he tried to heal.
一个他试图治愈的世界
A mission he never saw accomplished.
但他却无法看到成功的那一天了
It seems the destiny of great men to see their goals unfulfilled.
似乎伟人的命运 就是无法亲身成就他们的目标
Charles was more than a leader，more than a teacher。He was a friend.
查尔斯不仅仅是一位领袖， 他更是一位良师，一位益友
When we were afraid，he gave us strength.
当我们害怕时，他给与我们勇气
And when we were alone，he gave us a family.
而当我们孤单时，他给与我们家庭
He may be gone，but his teachings live on through us，his students.
他人虽已逝，但他的谆谆教诲 将长存于我们心中
Wherever we may go，we must carry on his vision.
无论我们身在何方 必将永远铭记他的理想
And that's a vision of a world united.
世界大同的理想
Kitty.
基蒂
Bobby.
鲍比
- You OK？- Yeah.
- 你还好吗？ - 还好
It's just… Xavier came to my house.
只不过…泽维尔当时来我家
He was the one that convinced me to come here.
是他说服我来这里
Yeah，me too.
对，我也一样
- We're all feeling the same way，you know。- No，Bobby，we're not.
- 我们的感觉都一样 - 不，鲍比，不一样
You have Rogue and I have…
你有小淘气而我…
You know，I just miss home.
我只是有些想家
The first snow and all that.
家乡的冬天
- Kitty，get up。Come with me。- Storm told us to stay in our rooms.
- 基蒂，起来，跟我来 - 暴风女让我们待在自己房里
Don't worry。We won't get caught.
别担心，我们不会被抓到
I mean，you can walk through walls，you know.
我是说，你能穿墙，是吧
Come on.
来吧
This place can be home too.
这里也能变成家乡
Thank you for this，Bobby.
谢谢，鲍比
You need a lift，kid？
要我送你吗，孩子？
No.
不
Where are you going？
你去哪儿？
You don't know what it's like to be afraid of your powers，afraid to get close to anybody.
你不会明白害怕自己的超能力 害怕接近任何人是什么感觉
Yeah，I do.
我明白
I want to be able to touch people，Logan.
我希望能去触摸别人，洛根
A hug。A handshake.
拥抱，握手
A kiss.
接吻
I hope you're not doing this for some boy.
希望你这么想不是为了某个男生
Look，if you wanna go，then go.
你想走，就走吧
Just be sure it's what you want.
只要你真的想清楚了
Shouldn't you be telling me to stay？
你是不是该劝我留下？
To go upstairs and unpack？
上楼打开行李
I'm not your father。I'm your friend.
我不是你父亲，我是你朋友
Just think about what I said，Rogue.
想想我的话，小淘气
Marie.
玛丽
Remember when we first met？Do you know what I saw when I looked at you？
记得我们初次见面？ 知道我从你身上看到了什么？
I saw the next stage in evolution both Charles and I dreamt of finding.
看到了我跟查尔斯都梦想 找到的更深层次的进化
And I thought to myself，「Why would Charles want to turn this goddess into a mortal？」
我问自己：“查尔斯为什么想把 这么一个女神变成凡人？”
I can manipulate the metal in this，
我能控制这里面的金属
but you，you can do anything.
但你能控制一切
Anything you can think of.
你能想到的一切
Jean.
琴
Enough.
够了
You sound just like him.
你刚才很像他
Jean，he wanted to hold you back.
琴，他想拖你后腿
- What do you want？- I want you to be what you are.
- 你想怎样？ - 我想你做你自己
As nature intended.
顺其自然
That cure is meant for all of us。If we want freedom，we must fight for it.
解药是针对我们所有人的 如果我们想要自由，就该奋起反抗
And that fight begins now.
现在就开始反抗
She shouldn't be here with us.
她不该跟我们在这
- Her power is completely unstable。- Only in the wrong hands.
- 她的能量一点不稳定 - 这要看在谁手里了
- And you trust her？She's one of them。- So were you once.
- 你信任她吗？她是他们中的一员 - 你以前也是
I stuck with you。Would have killed the professor if you'd given me the chance.
我一直追随着你，如果你给我机会 我愿意把教授干掉
Charles Xavier did more for mutants than you'll ever know.
查尔斯·泽维尔为变种人做的事 比你知道的多得多
My single greatest regret is that he had to die for our dream to live.
我最大的遗憾就是 他用死换来了我们梦想的生
So what now？What do we do？
现在干什么？我们怎么办？
Xavier started this school。Perhaps it's best that it end with him.
泽维尔创办了这所学校 让学校跟他一起结束比较好
- We'll tell the students they're going home。- Most of us don't have anywhere to go.
- 我们会告诉学生们让他们回家 - 我们绝大多数人无处可去
I can't believe this。I can't believe we're not going to fight for this school.
我无法相信，我无法相信 我们就这样放弃学校
I'm sorry。I know this is a bad time.
抱歉，我知道现在不是时候
I was told that this was a safe place for mutants.
我听说这里对变种人 来说是个安全的地方
It was，son.
曾经是，孩子
And it still is。We'll find you a room.
而且现在也是，我们给你找个房间
Hank，tell all the students the school stays open.
汉克，告诉所有学生 学校不会关门
Rogue.
小淘气
Hey，Rogue.
嘿，小淘气
- Hey，Pete。Have you seen Rogue？- Yeah，she took off.
- 嘿，皮特，看见小淘气了吗？ - 看见了，她走了
Logan.
洛根
- Logan。- Jean？
- 洛根 - 琴？
Logan。Where am l？Logan.
洛根，我在哪儿？洛根
Logan。Logan.
洛根，洛根
- Logan。- Stop.
- 洛根 - 别说了
Logan。Logan。Logan.
洛根，洛根，洛根
- Where are you going？- Where do you think？
- 你去哪儿？ - 你说呢？
- She's gone，Logan。She's not coming back。- You don't know that.
- 她走了，洛根，她不会回来了 - 你不知道
She killed the professor.
她杀了教授
It wasn't Jean。The Jean I know is still in there.
它不是琴 我认识的琴还在那
Listen，why can't you see the truth？
听着，你怎么就不能面对事实？
- Why can't you just let her go？- Because… because…
- 怎么就不能忘了她？ - 因为…因为…
Because you love her.
因为你爱她
She made her choice。Now it's time we make ours.
她做了她的选择 现在该我们做出选择了
So if you're with us，then be with us.
如果你跟我们一边， 那就跟我们呆在一起
We don't need a cure！We don't need a cure！
我们不需要解药！我们不需要解药！
Getting the cure so you can go back home to mommy and daddy？
得到解药，你就能回家找爸爸妈妈了？
I'm looking for someone.
我在找人
Oh，I get it。Your girlfriend.
哦，知道了，你女朋友
I figured she'd want the cure。She's pathetic.
我猜她是想要解药，真可怜
Come on，lceman.
来啊，冰人
Make a move.
出招吧
Same old Bobby。Still afraid of a fight.
你还是那个老鲍比，还是不敢打架
Today's attack was only our first salvo.
今天的袭击只是一个开始
So long as the cure exists，our war will rage.
只要解药继续存在， 我们的战争就会持续
Your cities will not be safe。Your streets will not be safe。You will not be safe.
你们的城市不再安全，你们的街道不再安全 你们自己也不再安全
And to my fellow mutants，I make you this offer…
而对于我的变种人同伴们 我建议
Join us or stay out of our way.
要么加入我们，要么袖手旁观
Enough mutant blood has been spilled already.
变种人的热血已经洒得够多了
We're trying to track them，sir。We're working hard.
我们在试图追踪他们 我们很努力
- We cannot let him do this。- You know I agree，sir.
- 我们不能让他这么为所欲为 - 我支持您，先生
This is now a national security matter。Seize and secure Worthington Labs.
现在这事关国家安全了 将沃星顿实验室戒严
I want troops armed with cure weapons deployed immediately.
我要立即大规模装备解药武器
And Trask，you have to find Magneto and stop him by any means necessary.
崔萨克，你必须找到万磁王 用一切必要手段阻止他
Magneto wants a war。We'll give him one.
万磁王要战争，我就给他一场
Let's go。Keep it moving.
快走，跟上
Turn in your old weapon。Turn in all metal.
交出你的旧武器，交出所有金属
Bayonets，magazines，dog tags.
匕首，弹夹，狗牌
Pick up your plastic weapons。Pick up your cure cartridge.
领取你的塑料制武器 领取你的解药弹夹
Absolutely no metal.
绝对不能有金属
We don't need a cure！We don't need a cure！
我们不需要解药！我们不需要解药！
They wish to cure us。But I say to you we are the cure.
他们想给我们解药 但我说，我们就是解药
The cure for that infirm，imperfect condition called homo sapiens.
胆小懦弱，满是缺点的智人的解药
They have their weapons.
他们有他们的武器
We have ours.
我们有我们的
We will strike with a vengeance and a fury that this world has never witnessed.
我们要将怒火化为动力 制造这世界前所未见的暴动与骚乱
And if any mutants stand in our way，we will use this poison against them.
如果任何变种人来阻止我们 我们就用这毒药来阻止他们
We shall go to Alcatraz lsland，
我们要直捣恶魔岛
take control of the cure，
接管解药
and destroy its source.
毁掉它的药方
And then nothing can stop us.
之后我们将所向无敌
Jean.
琴
I know the smell of your adamantium from a mile away.
老远就能闻到你的臭味
- I didn't come here to fight you。- Smart boy.
- 我不是来跟你打架的 - 聪明孩子
- I came for Jean。- You think I'm keeping her against her will？
- 我来找琴 - 你觉得我强迫她留下？
- She's here because she wants to be。- You don't know what you're dealing with.
- 她在这完全是自愿的 - 你不清楚你面对的是什么
I know full well。I saw what she did to Charles.
我很清楚 我看到了她如何对付查尔斯
And you stood there and let him die？
而你就站在旁边看着他死去？
- I'm not leaving here without her。- Yes，you are.
- 没有她我决不离开 - 不，你会离开
OK.
好的
Two minutes till rendezvous，Mr。President.
两分钟后结集，总统先生
We have a satellite feed of Magneto's base of operations.
我们有颗卫星监视 万磁王基地的行动
- How did we find it？- She gave us everything we wanted.
- 我们怎么找到的？ - 她全招了
Hell hath no fury like a woman scorned.
天下莫毒怨妇心
Approaching target dead ahead.
正前方就是目标
Set for 360-degree incursion.
准备全方位进攻
This is Team Leader to Bravo One。We are green to go.
这是B1小队长 我们准备好了
OK，send them in.
好，进攻
OK.
进攻
Freeze，mutants！Get your hands in the air！Hands in the air！
不许动，变种人！ 举起手来！举起手来！
OK。I give up.
好吧，我投降
Sorry，Mr。Secretary，it was a decoy.
抱歉，总统先生，是个圈套
If he's not there，then where the hell is he？
如果他不在那，那他在哪儿？
Worthington Labs。It ends where it began.
沃星顿实验室，将尘归尘、土归土了
- 100% - Are you sure the boy is still inside？- 100%.
- 你确定那孩子还在里面？
So how are we supposed to get there？'Cause I don't swim.
那我们怎么过去？ 我可不会游泳
Leave that to me.
这事交给我
Storm。Storm.
暴风女，暴风女
What are you doing back here？
你回来干啥？
I need help.
我需要帮忙
- You found her。- Yeah。She's with Magneto.
- 你找到她了 - 对，她跟万磁王在一起
- Where are they？- On the move。I know where they're going.
- 他们在哪儿？ - 在行动，我知道他们去哪儿
- You're saying you saw Magneto？- We gotta go。They're gonna attack Alcatraz.
- 你是说你看见万磁王了？ - 我们赶紧走，他们要袭击恶魔岛
- There are troops stationed on that island。- Not enough to stop him.
- 那边有一支军队守护 - 但不足以阻止他
Let's suit up.
我们去换衣服
- Hard to believe this once fit me。- If Magneto gets that cure，we can't stop him.
- 我以前竟然能穿下这个 - 如果万磁王得到了解药，我们就无能为力了
- Can you estimate how many he has？- An army。And Jean.
- 你能估计下他大概有多少人吗？ - 一支军队，还有琴
- His powers have limits，hers do not。- There's only six of us，Logan.
- 他的力量有限，但她的没有 - 这只有我们六个，洛根
Yeah。We're outnumbered.
对，我们人数不占优
I'm not gonna lie to you.
我不会骗你
But we lost Scott.
我们失去了斯科特
We lost the professor.
失去了教授
If we don't fight now，everything they stood for will die with them.
如果我们现在不战斗 他们为之奋斗的一切将随他们而去
I'm not gonna let that happen.
我不会让这种事发生
Are you？
你会吗？
Then we stand together.
那我们就并肩战斗
X-Men.
Ｘ战警
All of us.
我们所有人
We're in.
我们加入
Let's go.
我们走
- They're ready。- Yeah，I know.
- 他们准备好了 - 是，我知道
But are you ready to do what you need to do when the time comes？
但你准备好去做你到时该做的事了吗？
Dad，what's going on？
爸爸，怎么了？
It's an earthquake.
是地震
We're trapped.
我们被卡住了
Charles always wanted to build bridges.
查尔斯一直想建一座桥
My God.
老天爷啊
Fall back！Take cover！Fall back！
后退！隐蔽！后退！
The boy's in the southeast corner of the building.
那孩子在房子的东南角
- Well，then。- Let's take it down！
- 那好 - 把他们拿下！
In chess，the pawns go first.
象棋里，总是小卒打头阵
Humans and their guns.
人类和他们的武器
Plastic。They've learned.
塑料，他们学乖了
That's why the pawns go first.
所以要小卒打头阵
Target the bridge.
瞄准大桥
Fire！
发射
Arclight，use your shockwaves。Target those weapons.
弧光，使用你的冲击波 毁掉那些武器
- Oh，my stars and garters。- Go into stealth mode.
- 哎呀妈呀 - 进入隐形模式
- What about jets？Tanks？- Against Magneto？He'll turn them inside out.
- 用飞机大炮呢？ - 对抗万磁王？他能把它们捏瘪了
- Where are our ground troops？- 30 minutes away.
- 那我们的地面部队呢？ - 半小时的路程
Then God help us.
那上天会帮我们
They're coming for him.
是冲他来的
Don't ever do that again.
别再这么干了
You men cover the doors！
你们守住大门
Everybody get together！And hold this line！
大家站在一起，守住这条线
Traitors to their own cause.
被判自己的同类
Finish them！
干掉他们
Not yet.
还不是时候
Go inside and get the boy。And kill him.
进去找到那男孩，杀了他
With pleasure.
乐意效劳
Hold it！
顶住
He's going for the boy！
他去找那孩子了
Not if I get there first.
我能先找到
Kitty！
基蒂！
Come on.
来啊
Grow those back.
再长出来啊
Don't you know who I am？
你不知道我是谁吗？
I'm the Juggernaut，bitch.
我是圣像，贱人
Going somewhere？
去哪儿啊？
You're the guy that invented the cure，right？
就是你发明的解药吧？
Yes，I am.
对，是我
Girls.
姑娘们
No。Don't。Don't hurt him.
不，别，别伤害他
- No。Don't hurt him。- Let go of me。I didn't do anything.
- 别伤害他 - 让他去，我什么都没做
Calm down。Calm down.
冷静，冷静
Everything's gonna be OK.
一切都会好的
- I thought you were a diplomat。- As Churchill said，「There comes a time…」
- 我以为你就是个政客呢 - 就如丘吉尔所言：“听到召唤…”
Oh，you get the point.
哦，你知道我啥意思
Oh，no。Please，no，no，don't.
哦，不，求你们了，不，不，别
No.
不
No，don't worry。I'm here to help you。I'm going to get you out of here.
别害怕，我是来帮你的 我会带你出去
This way.
这边
- Oh，my God。What's going on？- Your powers won't work with me.
- 天，怎么回事？ - 在我身边你的超能力不管用
- Stay close，all right？- OK.
- 靠近点，好吗？ - 好
I'm the wrong guy to play hide-and-seek with.
玩藏猫猫你可找错人了
Who's hiding，dickhead？
谁藏了，蠢猪头
Don't。No.
别，不
Don't.
别
Please，don't do this。I only wanted to help you people.
求你们，别这样 我只是想帮你们
Do we look like we need your help？
我们像是需要帮助吗？
It's time to end this war.
是时候结束战斗了
Take cover.
躲起来
Get out of the way.
快躲起来
- Let's go，let's go。- Move.
- 我们走，我们走 - 快走
Go！Go！Go！
快！快！快！
We work as a team.
我们要并肩作战
Best defense is a good offence.
进攻就是最好的防守
Bobby，think you can take out your old friend？
鲍比，你能搞定你的老朋友吗？
Go ahead.
去吧
Storm，we're gonna need some cover.
暴风女，我们需要点掩护
Right.
好
You're in over your head，Bobby.
你完蛋了，鲍比
Maybe you should go back to school.
没准你该回学校再学学
You never should have left.
你就不该辍学
This is it.
是时候了
Hey.
嘿
Make it a strike.
使劲点
You never learn，do you？
你就不长记性是吧
Actually，I do.
实际上，我长了
I'm…
我…
One of them？
他们中的一员？
This is what they want for all of us.
这就是他们想对我们做的
It's over，Jean.
都结束了，琴
It's over.
结束了
No！Don't shoot！
不，别开枪
No！
不
Everybody get out of there！
所有人都离开这
Bobby！
鲍比！
What have I done？
我这是干了什么
I'm the only one who can stop her。Get everyone to safety.
只有我能阻止她 带大家离开这
Go.
去吧
Jean！
琴！
I know you're still there！
我知道你还在！
You would die for them？
你原为他们而死？
No，not for them.
不，不是为他们
For you.
为你
Save me.
救救我
I love you.
我爱你
You're back.
你回来了
I'm sorry.
对不起
I had to.
我必须去
- This isn't what I wanted。- I know.
- 这不是我想要的 - 我知道
It's what I want.
是我想要的
Hey.
嘿
Good to see you，buddy.
见到你真好，小伙计
With the thanks of a grateful nation
为致以全民的谢意
I introduce our new ambassador to the United Nations，
我向大家介绍我们 新任驻联合国大使
and the representative to the world for all United States citizens，
全部美国公民在世界上的代表
human and mutant alike，
无论人类还是变种人
Dr。Hank McCoy.
汉克·迈考伊博士
Way to go，fur ball.
适合你，毛球
Morning.
早
Hello，Moira.
你好，默瑞亚
Charles.
查尔斯